Don't move.
- This is my mate, Justin.
- Hey there.
- Hey.
- And I love him.
All I want is what you want.
To have these people locked up,
so they can't do any more harm
to anyone else.
Justin, I think I may
have taken a wrong turn.
Do you want to talk about this properly?
- That's why I'm here.
- No, I mean, properly.
I'm not sure what's
supposed to be going on here.
I'm completely lost.
That's why we're here.
To help you understand
how lost you really are.
How am I supposed to trust
you if you don't trust me?
I will be back.
I'm a copper, we're on the same side.
I don't think you're going to shoot me.
I warned you not to make me your enemy!
- I warned you!
- No. Don't you... don't you...
Hey. Get up!
Justin.
Please.
Oh, God. Key. Key. Key.
Are you ok? You ok?
Mary.
What did John say to you exactly?
He said... he said he was busy.
And that I should meet
him here, at his place.
No.
Erin?
Man down.
Justin Ripley.
So what is it with John Luther
and the people he loves?
John, I don't know what to say.
I don't have the words.
Where is Mary?
John Luther,
you're under arrest for the murder
of Detective Sergeant Justin Ripley
and the attempted murder of Mary Day.
Mary! Hey, Mary. Mary!
Hold on!
Ok.
From this side of the table, it looks like
there's two people who
could incriminate you,
one of which is now dead
by the hand of Tom Marwood.
And Mary Day would be...
had I not intervened.
And you're welcome, by the way.
You told her where to go, John.
You told her where
and when.
And I think you did that
because you wanted Marwood
to kill her for you.
Yesterday,
a few hours before he shot
and killed Justin Ripley,
you spoke for some time to Mr Marwood.
Your report notes that
during this conversation,
Tom Marwood asked for more time.
"Give me two days."
And then you let him go.
Which makes me wonder,
what was the quid pro quo?
Shut your mouth.
You let Marwood
run free to kill his paedophiles and his
scumbags.
That's no skin off your nose.
No humans involved.
But then in exchange,
does you a favour.
He cleans up your mess.
I loved him.
He's got too many friends.
We'll have to move him.
What is this, John?
I don't know, George.
Stay here.
Erin!
Wotcher.
'Detective Ripley has been hailed
a hero by his colleagues after
'he was shot point blank in the
chest by vigilante Thomas Marwood
'who has been branded a coward... '
Oh.
If you're going to go on the
run you're going to have to, er,
lose the coat.
It's my lucky coat.
Lucky?!
Right. Well, I would take it
back to the shop, if I was you.
Get your money back.
It's obviously defective.
This is a nice place.
Is it yours?
Don't be silly.
Alice, what are you doing here?
I saw the news.
Where have you been?
Berlin.
I don't believe you.
Oh, you should.
I assumed you'd need it, eventually.
Not yet.
After Marwood.
Then I'm done.
Why? Because he killed your puppy?
Oh, that's why you're here?
To rub my nose in it?
No.
I came to help the people you love.
I'm sorry?
You assert this fabulous
moral conscience, John.
This adherence to unwritten
law. Yet, time and again,
it devastates the people you claim
to hold dear, but you don't stop.
It seems to me your conscience
has killed more people than I have.
Well, you know, you say "escape," George,
but to me, this looks more like
the scene of a violent abduction.
By Marwood?
Presumably.
Why not pop him here?
The way he did Ripley?
Well, we won't know that
until we ask him, will we?
In the meantime,
somewhere out there,
there is a police officer
in the hands of a known police killer.
Well, either way, Martin...
we both want DCI Luther
returned to us
at the earliest opportunity.
A search is under way.
Then widen it.
You know, George,
the Tom Marwood investigation
is under my command,
and God help you
if you interfere with it
or question my allocation of resources.
DCI Luther does have some loyal friends,
- doesn't he?
- Oh, yes, he does.
'One officer was shot dead
and another badly injured.
'In what the police say
may be a related incident,
'Milan Knizac has been
attacked in Mortlake Prison.
'Knizac is serving a life sentence
'for the murder of Caitlin
Marwood, Tom Marwood's late wife.
'Caitlin Marwood was raped
and murdered by Milan Knizac
'four years ago, after he
was released from prison
'less than halfway through
a nine-year sentence... '
- What do you want?
- Don't move!
So where are we going?
We're taking you somewhere safe,
just to be sure.
But you can't honestly think
John would ever hurt me?
So where did you go?
Oh, here and there. Got married.
- You got what?
- Married.
Why?
Does it add a tingle of the
illicit to the conversation?
It adds a tingle of
disbelief, is what it does.
- Erm, where did you and...
- Bertrand.
A conference in Sao Paolo.
Oh, he was intensely intellectual.
- He "was"?
- Sadly, he passed away.
Some little girls grow up wanting ponies.
I always wanted to be a widow.
So, what about you?
Have you found someone, hmm?
Yeah. Kind of.
And is she interesting?
- To whom?
- Me!
- I don't know.
- Well,
I imagine she wouldn't be, terribly.
She wouldn't be some kind of Zoe surrogate.
You've got enough self-knowledge
to avoid that trap.
So she's a pixie.
- A what?
- A pixie.
A sprite.
A daydream of the life you
imagine you want to live.
Oh, dear, I feel a bit sorry for her.
You don't feel sorry for anyone.
Well, quite.
But in principle, I pity her.
She's not what you want.
She's what you want to want.
What is it I want exactly?
We're not talking about that.
We're talking about Pixie.
- Pix... her name is Mary.
- I know.
'The officer shot dead
last night has been named
'as Detective Sergeant Justin Ripley.
'Detective Sergeant Ripley is
believed to have been killed
'by Tom Marwood who first appealed to
the public in this video yesterday.'
'Four years ago,
'she was raped and murdered
by a man called Milan Knizac.'
This him?
This is him.
Goodness gracious me.
What a needy little fishy.
Oh, he's got a hero complex.
He needs public opinion to
justify his own actions to himself.
So what's the plan, Stan?
I take away everything he wants.
What does he want?
To avenge his wife.
To be admired. To become a martyr.
All to make his wife's
death mean something.
You'd take all that from him?
Yeah.
That's cruel.
It's the cruellest thing I can think of.
Ok.
But if any police
aren't out there looking for him,
they're out there looking for you. So...
how do we even begin?
Well.
First step.
You're Thomas Marwood.
You want to kill the man
that killed your wife.
But Milan Knizac is in prison.
So how would you do it?
With leverage.
Give me a lever long enough
and a fulcrum on which to place it,
and...
I can move the world.
Nat?
Nat?!
Hello?
It's not an easy thing, is it,
when your wife is taken from you?
Well, do as I tell you
and you'll get her back.
What is this place?
Nobody knows we're here, Mary.
Not John,
none of his friends.
So, as long as we stay here,
we're safe, ok?
Just... try and make yourself comfortable.
Benny.
Schenk.
Well, never let it be said
that you are less than
audacious, Miss Morgan.
Well, I've got an issue
with impulse control, Martin.
It's in the genes apparently.
You know, Miss Morgan, I must
remind you, I'm a police officer
and you are a fugitive from justice.
And that, by walking in here,
you have, by default,
surrendered your liberty.
Well, you're entitled to send me back.
I wouldn't take it personally.
- Besides, I'd only escape.
- I have no doubt.
Meanwhile, John will be in prison.
Or dead
at the hands of Tom Marwood.
Now, me, I'm as guilty as sin.
Name it, I've done it.
But...
John's as innocent as I am culpable.
So I suppose the question I'm
here to ask is which matters more?
Punishing my guilt?
Or proving John's innocence?
Now John
has asked me to tell you that Tom Marwood
won't allow himself to be arrested.
He intends to commit suicide by cop,
to die a martyr to his own cause.
Now John knows how to bring him in alive.
But...
he's going to need
your support.
What exactly does he need?
For starters,
anything you have on Milan Knizac.
Oh,
and I'm going to need a personnel file.
Thank you, boys.
Why did you come back?
I beg your pardon?
You heard.
I told you. I saw the news.
Alice, come on.
None of this Berlin bullshit.
You've been in London for weeks.
What makes you say that?
I saw a receipt for those boots.
I wanted something.
- What?
- You.
- Alice, Mary and I...
- Oh, do be serious.
You'll be bored silly
by the end of the week.
- You and I are...
- What?
Well...
- What do I do?
- Let me have it, please.
Erin, no. Leave it, it's fine.
If it's him, it's important we know
what he says. Ok.
Answer.
Hello?
'Mary.
Where are you?'
I can't tell you that, John.
They...
they won't let me tell you.
All right. Ok, of course they won't.
Look, I won't be long, ok?
I just want to tell you something
and I want you to hear
me say it, all right?
I haven't done any of the
things they're saying I did.
Are you ok?
Yeah.
Hi, yeah, we've got a trace on DCI Luther.
Well, look, don't be scared.
George Stark's a bit of a dick
but he means well, I guess.
And Erin Grey, well, she just...
she's got me all wrong, all right.
But she's a good woman and...
when push comes to shove, you can,
- well, you can trust her.
- Ok.
Are they with you now?
What about you? Are you, um...
Ok?
Yeah.
Benny...
Guv, can I have a word?
- Huh?
- Now, please.
What the hell was that?
Letting her talk to him?
What if he traces the call?
Oh, my God.
You're trying to lure
him here! Are you mad?
- How is she?
- Safe.
Did you find anyone?
It'll be in one of these.
Ok. Ok.
Oh, I'm bored of this already. Ok.
Milan Knizac is in the prison hospital
because someone cut his throat.
Joe Green has got access to him.
He's a prison doctor.
He's also married to Natalie
Green, who's pregnant.
So that's who I'd go for,
if I wanted Milan Knizac dead.
And I needed leverage.
- Who are you?
- Police.
He said no police! No police!
Just stay there, just stay there.
Alice, Marwood's gone.
We missed him, all right. He's long gone.
All right, so what did he say exactly?
That I should report to work tomorrow
and kill Milan Knizac
with a lethal injection.
And if you don't?
He'll make sure that what Knizac
did to his wife is done to mine.
- He said that if I called the police...
- I'm not police.
I was the police. But I'm not any more.
Who the hell are you then?
I'm the man that's going
to bring Natalie back.
Where are you going? You
can't just leave me here!
If I take you with me,
you'll do something stupid.
You won't be able to help
yourself. You love Natalie, right?
What about him? Tom
Marwood? What about him?
He won't know what hit him.
Benny, small change of plans.
I need you to get a
trace on the last number
who called this phone.
Yeah.
Hello.
This is
Ryan Clark.
He was over the limit,
high on meth,
he was banned from driving and behind
the wheel of a stolen car
when he ran over and killed
a 12-year-old boy.
Mr Clark then fled the scene.
He was in prison for less than five years.
This is not about Ryan Clark's rights...
this is about our responsibilities.
This is about us doing for ourselves
what the state refuses to do for us.
People like me have tried to be reasonable,
we have tried to be reasonable
but nobody's listened.
Oh, boy.
He really does need the
world to love him, doesn't he?
So now a 12-year-old boy is dead.
My wife is dead.
Many other people are dead.
Well, no more.
I have a list of people like Ryan Clark
and I will execute them
at a rate of one a day,
every day, until the Prime Minister agrees
to hold a referendum
on the death penalty. Now,
that's all I'm asking for,
is for the people of this country
to be given a choice.
It's not like you gave
Justin Ripley a choice, is it?
That man's death is on your head.
Well, I don't see how that can be right.
I didn't ask you to kill him.
I warned you to stay away.
You can't hold me accountable
if you choose not to listen.
See, the thing is, I
can hold you accountable.
Me being a copper and all that.
- What... g... give me that camera.
- Oh, I don't think so.
Give me that camera or I will shoot him!
No, you won't, Thomas.
Not on camera,
because people do hate a cop killer
and you so very much want to be admired,
which is a defect, really,
in a multiple murderer but...
- Do not move another step.
- She's got a point there, Tom.
I mean, you're not going to
shoot an innocent man, a cop.
Not for the world to see.
Turn off the camera!
Turn off that camera now!
Why don't you just stop
all this, all right?
And tell us where you're
keeping Natalie Green.
Who has she ever hurt in her life? No-one.
Not to mention the fact
- that she's pregnant.
- Shut up!
- Come on, Tom. Come on!
Just let her go.
You being the... the
defender of the innocent.
Stop, stop! Turn it off!
Whoever the hell you
are, turn off that camera.
Tell her to turn it off.
Look. Look, just put it down. Put it down.
Put it down and turn it
off. Do as the man says.
You hear me, do it, do it, do it.
Now move away, move away.
Oh, what are you going
to do now, DCI Luther?
What are you going to do now, Tom?
She's not going to come back, you know.
- I don't care if she does. I've got the camera.
- Problem is,
the world is going to see that
you're not actually a hero.
You're just a cop killer
that would kidnap a pregnant woman.
I mean, come on, that's nasty!
She's gone, Tom. There's
no point running after her.
She's gone.
Bingo.
You, you! Bring her back!
- Bring her back!
- Tom,
it's not like I can actually
show the tape to anyone really.
W... why not? Why not?
Let's say I did. What do you stand to lose?
You... you still can kill Natalie Green.
I don't have her, you do.
So, er, I've got what you want.
And you've got what I want.
So what do we do now?
You take me to Natalie.
All right, you let her go.
What and then you, you
give me back the tape?
Give it right back.
Liar.
See, you forgot
that I had stolen...
I stole your phone, remember?
So I have heard all those
lovely, intimate messages from...
Mary Day, was it?
So,
you get me that tape,
and I give you back
your Mary.
Ok?
I'm a police officer.
Give us that phone, I need that phone.
- What are you doing?
- I just need this phone.
Hello?
Put George on the phone now.
On speaker. Just do it!
Ok. Ok. You're on speaker.
You have to get Mary
out of there right now!
Do you understand me?
I think we've had enough of that.
What are you doing?
George?
He's trying to lure us out of here.
Please, trust me.
Boss, you need to get
C019 down to Paragon...
Paragon Towers right now.
Get them there.
Hello, Tinkerbell.
It's John.
There's nothing to worry about.
We need you to stay here, ok?
- Who the hell are you?
- Shh.
What's that?
Proof you shouldn't need
of the kind of man John Luther actually is.
When Stark and the lesbian get back,
you show them this.
Oh, and if you ever
betray him like this again...
I'll kill you and eat you.
How does that sound?
What's your name?
What?
Are you Mary?
Are you Mary?!
Yes. Yes, yes, I'm Mary.
Did John send you to do this?
To do what?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- John Luther.
I know what Mary sounds like.
I've heard her voice.
You don't sound like Mary.
I am Mary. I'm Mary. I'm Mary.
Show me your wallet.
Now!
What are you doing?
So I've got bullets, but no gun.
That's quite Zen.
You're Erin Grey.
D... don't.
Find me a nail.
W... what kind of nail?
A nail nail. As in, a hammer and...
Ok.
- Mary?
- Yeah?
Is the door locked?
Stop! Stop, stop, stop.
Police officer, open the door.
Come on, come on. Get out.
Give me the nail.
Shh. Breathe, Tinkerbell.
I don't know who you are.
Open the door.
- What?
- Gently.
Close.
Lean all your weight on the door.
Nice try. Nice try, Mary.
Tom!
Isn't it time we knocked this on the head?
Both of you. Move. Move! Move!
Hey! Come on!
Come on. Move it! Move it!
Mary, it's going to be all right, ok?
Tom,
where's Natalie Green?
Well, I'm going to be dead in a moment,
so I suppose you're going to have
to live with the never knowing.
No, don't punish me by hurting
Natalie, ok? She's done nothing.
Who the hell do you think you are?
To walk in here,
after what you've done to me,
and dictate what I can and can't do?
No! Tom, don't. Stop, don't.
You can choose, you can have one.
Sorry?
I said pick one.
- Why?
- So you know what it feels like.
Time's running out.
Please don't do this.
- It's your last chance.
- I can't.
I can't pick one.
- Then you'll walk out of here alone.
- Tom.
Please.
It's ugly, isn't it? Being impotent.
Being degraded
by a violent man that
you'll never get to punish.
Now pick.
No.
Fine.
Stop!
Just stop pointing that
gun at her head. Stop.
- Then choose.
- I can't choose one.
Five.
- Four.
- Please!
Three.
Two.
- One!
- All right!
All right!
Have you chosen?
Yes.
Then say it.
Say her name.
Say it now!
Alice.
Say it again.
- Shoot Alice.
- Say it again!
Alice.
No!
Oops.
Sorry,
couldn't resist.
Run! Run. Run. Get out of here. Run! Go on.
Go!
Now, if I let this go,
you'll die. Which is
what you want, isn't it?
- Eh? But if I apply pressure just here...
- No.
- There's a good chance you'll live.
- No!
Please. Please. Don't. Please.
- Please.
- Beg me.
- Beg me!
- I'm begging you.
Then where's Natalie? Where is she?
- Please.
- Come on, Tom. Come on, Tom.
The medics are coming,
- they're going to save your life.
- No.
She's in, she's in Cathay Street.
- How do I know you're not lying?
- No. It's true. It's true.
- How do I know? Is it true?
- Please. Just let go. Please.
- You're ready to go?
- Yeah,
I'm ready. I'm ready. I'm ready.
Please...
Not on your nelly.
Medic!
- No!
- Medic!
I need him alive, put
pressure right here. Here!
All right, upstairs.
Sir.
Natalie?
We're the police.
You're safe now.
Hold on, hold on.
Boss.
What's happening?
They arrested Alice Morgan.
Where is she?
- And Mary?
- She left you a message.
She gave you this?
She put it into my hand herself.
Benny, I appreciate it, pal.
Where you going, boss? She went that way.
I just want to say sorry to Alice.
There's been a mix up over who's who.
I expect they'll, er,
they'll work it out in a couple hours.
I don't care what she's done,
John.
She saved my life.
So you should probably...
go.
Yeah.
I should do that.
- I...
- I know.
Me too.
Go on. Go.
It was clever. The choice you made.
Marwood?
Alive.
Suffering.
Good.
You really do need to lose the coat.
So...
now what?
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -