Last season, on "The Flash"...
Hey, Mom and Dad.
If you're watching this,
it means that something went wrong.
- Mom, what's happening?
- A new timeline is setting in.
- Thank you for everything.
- I love you.
Look, Kamilla, I don't want
to keep this from you anymore.
If being Vibe is a part
of the life you want,
I would never get in the way of that.
I wanna take the cure.
Killer Frost and I are
really gonna miss Vibe.
Me, too.
Dad...
I would like my
replacement to be you, Joe.
- As captain?
- Captain Joe West.
None of you can stop
what's been set into motion
because nothing you can do
can alter what's about to happen.
It's a system-wide power surge.
It's coming from the Time Vault.
- Are we under attack?
- I don't know.
Whatever's going on
started the moment we left.
I wasn't perfect.
Please remember that I love you both...
and I always will.
And I always will.
And I always will... always... always...
Barry, Nora's message.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
Why is it every time I come to visit
there's always a crisis?
Comes with the meta-territory.
750 mph. He's getting faster.
Who is this guy, anyway?
An old family friend.
His name's Godspeed, and
he's from the future.
He's like a fake speedster.
What's that?
The real deal.
Kick his butt, Barry!
Done and doner.
Who are you and what are
you doing in Central City?
He's just like the others: no
language skills, just noise.
- Lovely.
- What was that?
The fourth Godspeed
we've caught this summer
and still no sign of Mr. August Heart.
Just another dummy who
can't communicate anything
beyond modem speak.
All right, I'm clocking out.
Why don't you drop off
G4 at Iron Heights, Barry?
I don't think we're figuring
out this mystery today.
This is nice, Dad.
We should do this way more often.
Agreed.
Hey, before I forget,
congratulations on "The Citizen."
Yeah, well, you know,
there's millions of
people in Central City
and I've only got a couple
hundred thousand subscribers.
You know, I'm no CCPN.
Well, not yet, but in about ten years
it'll be a Pulitzer Prize-winning empire.
Baby steps, Dad.
Mm, damn, this is good.
You know you can't get drunk.
I don't even care,
that's how good this is.
Never fear, the party's here!
We brought my famous ambrosia salad
and veggie dogs for Ralph.
Guys, Ralph's still in Peru.
Or Monaco... or Texas?
All that for a missing person's case?
That's dedication.
Guys, guys, what are we doing?
Baby Jenna is napping
like a little angel
and I have creamed corn,
I have candied yams,
I have collard greens.
- Baby, let's eat.
- Yum!
Yeah!
- How's the MAC coming?
- There's mac and cheese too?
No, the Mental Augmentation Chamber.
Basically, it allows us
to tap into the Speed Force
to boost Barry's cognitive abilities.
It would allow him to see every
possible outcome to a scenario
at the same time.
So speed-thinking.
Which means we'll be able
to catch all the bad guys faster.
With all the ones that
you brought in this summer,
Barry, the DA's office can
barely keep up with you.
Hey, since the MAC's done,
we should take it for a test run.
Absolutely not.
You know we're still
working out diagnostics.
We could put in a few hours tonight,
get a head start.
Barry...
If there's anything I've learned
since leaving Vibe behind,
it's that we all have a
work-life balance to protect,
and right now, mine is
tipping towards more beer.
Besides, I still gotta
tweak the mainframe
and I can't do that without...
Uh...
Every time.
- My tablet.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
I'm gonna go get that beer.
Hey, so the last time
I talked to you guys,
you seemed good.
You guys good?
Um...
we were devastated at first,
but Nora's only gone for right now.
We're gonna have kids someday
and then we'll have another Nora.
Yeah, I think knowing that
we have a second chance
makes all the difference.
I gotta go, a break-in
at Eastside Industrial.
Dad, um, I meant to ask you,
what did you do with those boxes
that were in the back of the garage?
Oh, he finally threw them away.
Thank you very much.
Okay, I gotta make a call.
Guys, I'm sorry, I actually
have to sneak out too.
A friend of mine from med
school needs my support.
Thanks for having me, it was delicious.
Bye, Caitlin.
You notice ain't nobody help clean up?
My name is Ramsey Rosso,
and my mother, Dr. Rachel Rosso,
was everything to me.
When I was seven,
I skidded out pretty badly
on a bike she bought me
for my birthday.
Imagine a scared kid
with two scraped knees
and a bloody nose.
When Mum found me,
she picked me right up,
she brushed me off,
and told me to get back
on my bike and ride.
I tried, but I couldn't.
It was almost like I was paralyzed,
it hurt so bad.
That's when she told
me that I would heal.
That I must never let
a little pain stop me
from getting to where
I needed to go in life,
and she was right.
I did heal.
Enough to grow up
and follow in her footsteps.
And even though a
beautiful life was cut short
when she lost her
battle to heal herself...
She is still helping me to get
to where I need to go today.
And for that, I will always be grateful.
Thank you, Jonathan.
Ramsey, hi.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
Your mother was an incredible woman.
I'm gonna miss her.
It means so much that you came.
Mum actually saw something
of herself in you.
Probably because you're
both overachievers.
Your hands are so cold.
Are you all right?
Yeah, sorry, I'm fine.
Um, probably just coming
down with something.
Well, I hope not.
- Doctors make rubbish patients.
- Mm.
It was nice to see you.
Eh, Caitlin?
Things have been a bit, um, crazy.
Do you fancy coming around
for a cuppa sometime?
You know, for a proper catch-up.
I could really use someone
to talk to right now.
Of course, any time.
Just give me a call.
Well, my log says that
your father's stuff
should have ended up
somewhere around here.
There it is.
Must be pretty important.
Yeah, it is.
Thanks.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
H-hang on!
I've got you!
You okay?
What the hell?
I missed you last night.
Are you sure you're okay?
Yeah.
What were you doing out here anyway?
I was following up on a lead.
"The Citizen" got a tip
that there were a series
of junkyard robberies.
People file police
reports for stolen trash?
Yeah, well, you know,
not everything that's here is garbage.
Everything here is garbage!
I hate garbage.
Okay, have fun with Ghostbusters.
- I'll see you at home.
- Mm-hmm.
What do you got?
This site is littered...
no pun intended...
with gamma rays and magnetar fields.
What are you saying?
Iris was attacked by a...
Yeah, a frakkin' black hole.
That is a whole lot of
information to disseminate.
No one's ever
extrapolated this much data
from a black hole before.
We can be the first.
Come on, we're Team Flash!
What did you put in his coffee?
Okay, a black hole just showed up
and nearly swallowed Iris.
So let's crunch the numbers,
find out where it went.
I'm sorry, are we looking
at the same screen?
Creating a search algorithm
for this is gonna be like
deciphering a mystery
wrapped up in an enigma.
Then it's a good thing
that "mystery" is my middle name.
The name's Dibny...
Ralph Dibny.
Welcome back, Ralph.
- It's good to see you, man.
- Nice threads.
- Where'd you get them?
- Picked this up in the Opal.
A missing person's case
sent you all the way to Opal City?
And beyond, my friend.
A summer spent
undercover rubbing Rolexes
with the wealthy elite.
Did you guys know it's pronounced "yacht"
and not "yah-kt"?
- Yep.
- God, I missed you.
Anyway, just following
any leads that might help
explain the disappearance
of Sue Dearbon.
I don't think I've ever seen
you this devoted to a case.
Me neither, but this
one is a real tragedy.
Maybe it was the look of desperation
in her parents' eyes when they begged me
to find their daughter.
So, uh, what's new in Central City?
We are trying to track a black hole.
Of course you are.
We were just about to start
decoding this data stream.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Ugh, I'm sorry, sorry.
Been having these
random frost-outs lately.
- For how long?
- All summer.
It's happened twice in
the last couple of days.
Cait, you're probably overworked.
Maybe take a time out?
A friend of mine did
want to meet for coffee.
- Ramsey?
- Yeah.
It's never easy losing a parent.
Maybe you should take him up on it.
I'll give him a call.
Ah, found it.
Theft report for Leawood
and New Brighton junkyard.
See, I have a system.
You're a hoarder, but I love you.
Iris.
Huh, these don't seem
to have anything to
do with the black hole.
They're just run-of-the-mill human thefts.
Well, you have a list
of persons of interest,
- in any case.
- Yeah, thank you.
Um, I'll get right on this.
Iris?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
I... I don't know, maybe
I'm still a little shaken up
from the black hole.
I'll be fine, thank you.
You remembered how I like my lattes.
With a bit of cinnamon, just like Mum.
You know, of all her
CC Hospital residents,
she really took a special liking to you.
She was the first person
to realize that I was
into cutting-edge tech.
It was her letter of recommendation
that started my career at S.T.A.R. Labs.
I couldn't save her, Cait.
Had to watch as her body betrayed her.
Do you know how HLH works?
Then you know the cancer
literally boils you
from the inside out.
Can you imagine what
that must have felt like?
Watching her suffer...
That's my last memory of her.
Don't let it be.
What you said at the funeral
about how brave she was?
Remember that.
I lied.
Truth is, she was a coward.
What do you mean?
As a doctor, she knew her
chances of surviving were slim,
so she just started ticking
things off her bucket list.
Isn't that a good thing?
She should have gone down fighting.
Instead, she ran away.
I didn't.
In HLH, white blood cells attack
the body's immune system.
A median survival rate after diagnosis
was two to six months.
Not anymore.
Oh, my God, this is a potential cure.
But what's the bonding agent
strengthening the body's defenses?
Dark matter.
I know what you're thinking, Cait.
I thought the same
thing, too... at first.
But I have been running
simulations for months,
and they all show the same results.
My cure will work.
Or turn them into meta-humans
against their will.
But I can save lives.
I just need the dark matter
to start human trials.
And that's why you wanted
to get coffee with me.
S.T.A.R. Labs has the dark matter I need
to take the next step;
you have access to it.
Ramsey, your research,
it's groundbreaking,
but using dark matter?
That's a deal-breaker.
It wasn't when you made
the meta-human cure.
That was different. We
were trying to protect them.
Well, what about the rest of us?
I'm sorry. I really am.
But my answer is still no.
She didn't have to die, Cait.
No one with HLH does,
because you could help me stop it.
Frost, where are you?
- How you feeling?
- Like I should be dead.
That's not gonna
happen. We're Team Flash.
We always watch each other's backs.
We always keep each other safe.
Meanwhile, over here in the real world,
our black hole keeps growing up.
Only next time it pops up,
it won't just be Jitters.
The whole city could be in danger.
Why did this thing show
up outside Jitters, anyway?
What does a coffee shop have
in common with a junkyard?
I think I know who can tell us.
Okay, so I followed up with CCPD's list
of junkyard robberies.
Ten of them were persons of interest,
nine were career
criminals, but this one guy,
a scientist, was let go with a warning
after being caught
stealing old lab equipment.
Team Flash, meet Chester P. Runk.
Hey, what up, party people?
Welcome to a world where all are welcome
and anything, including the
scientifically impossible,
can and probably will happen.
I'm your boy
Chugga-Chugga-Chugga-Chugga Chester...
I really like him.
With knowledge from the
bleeding edge of physics
and beyond-beyond-beyond.
I've been working on that echo.
And... and yes, as usual,
I am fueled by some...
mm, damn fine coffee
from everyone's favorite beanery.
Poured, of course, to, uh, perfection
by a certain special someone.
Huh, huh, huh?
Uh, no, WookieLover77, I...
I have not asked her out yet,
but I got my punch card, okay?
Three more Vibe-achinos and
I'm making my move, baby.
I'm making my move, baby!
Okay, he talks about
Natalie for a while, so...
There we go.
Is he building what
I think he's building?
Behold, believers:
a gravitational wave emitter
powered by a modulated neutrino charger.
In other words,
"Time to call some aliens."
- He built this in his garage?
- Using nothing but trash.
What a legend. Oh, he's turning it on.
Uh... uh, no.
No, no, no, that's not
supposed to do that.
Oh, crap. Uh, hold on.
Okay, not exactly getting
the supervillain vibe
from our boy Chester here.
He opened a black hole by accident.
And what about Chester? Is he okay?
Well, police reports show
that EMTs took him to the ER,
but then after that the trail goes cold.
Just a tiny question here:
how do we destroy a black hole?
Well, I am not a doctor,
but I'm gonna assume in this case
that "negative" means a positive.
Not if it means being clueless
about why my powers won't work.
Did anything out of the
ordinary happen recently?
I went to my friend Ramsey's
mom's funeral yesterday.
Anything unusual about the service?
No, it was a lovely service
for an inspiring woman.
Then, today, I nearly
got sucked into oblivion.
Has our frosty femme fatale
ever refused to come
out like this before?
The last time I can think of
is right after my dad died.
Right.
So you think funeral
plus nearly getting
sucked into a black hole
equals Killer Frost is afraid of dying?
Maybe...
but I know we're gonna figure this out.
This place creeps me out.
Will this sort you out?
Nice doing business with you.
Whoever pissed you off
won't be a problem anymore.
Chester P. Runk is here?
Ward nurses say he's been
catatonic since he arrived.
Just involuntary muscle spasms.
Chester?
My name is Iris West-Allen, I'm a reporter.
Chester, can you hear me?
He was our only lead.
Iris.
You lost something of Nora's
last night, didn't you?
Something that Joe
accidentally threw away,
it ended up at that junkyard.
I just miss her so much.
Every day, every minute.
And I know that is selfish because...
one day I may get to see Nora again.
But it won't be our Nora, you know?
The one that we knew, the
one that we have pictures of,
the one that we grew
to love, you know...
That Nora is gone forever.
And I guess because of
that you know, I just...
I don't know how I'm supposed to feel.
Iris, you do not get to
cheat the grieving process
just because you know you're
gonna see Nora again someday.
Yeah, you're right.
I guess I just haven't been able
to put into words how I've been feeling.
Iris?
What is it?
It's Chester.
Oh, my God.
You're looking at the world's first
inverse mass angular momentum disruptor,
but we can just call
it a stellar grenade.
Cool.
So this will destroy the black hole?
As long as it doesn't get much bigger,
this will reverse the hole's
mass-collecting properties,
causing it to...
Implode.
Just toss it in the event horizon;
hasta lasagna,
don't get any on you.
We can't.
If we destroy it, we're
gonna kill Chester too.
You sure about this?
Yeah, the corona's flair
matched the exact cadence
of Chester's fingers.
So the black hole and
Chester are connected?
Actually, I think Chester
is the black hole.
Watch this: so normally,
stimuli enters the brain
through the sensory area,
goes up to the temporal lobe,
and then back around,
but watch what happens
in Chester's brain.
It starts in the right area,
but halfway through its
rotation, it disappears.
I think I know where it's going.
You're looking at a map of
the negative ionic energy
inside the black hole.
Watch what happens when an energy pulse
travels along its tendrils.
See how it stops halfway?
The black hole is the other
half of Chester's mind.
It's his consciousness.
Maybe it's been showing up
in places that hold an
emotional attachment for him,
like the junkyard where he
stole stuff for his projects.
He's got a crush on a girl at Jitters.
Okay, so all we have to
do is get Chester's mind
out of the black hole,
reunite it with his body,
and once his condition stabilizes,
the black hole should just collapse.
Right, but they don't exactly
teach that in med school.
Okay, but we can't just let Chester die.
We have to do something.
Look, I don't like saying it,
but I think we need to consider it.
Cisco, I know where you're going.
And you know we already have a way
of beating this before
it gets any bigger.
- We're not discussing this.
- You think I like saying this?
I don't, but if we don't
find a solution for this
and find one now, we're
gonna have to make a choice
down the line, and it's
either gonna be Chester
or it's gonna be
everyone in Central City.
I'm not losing anyone else!
I'm... let's find another way.
_
Where's the meltdown?
We gotta talk.
What is your problem?
My problem is, we needed you,
and you were holed up in
your Snow-tress of Solitude.
I mean, you even refused
to come out at Jitters.
Flash was there, so spare
me the little hallway chat...
and I'm not afraid of dying.
I know that, but you
are afraid of living.
Thomas' death, the funeral,
what happened at Jitters:
all those things happened to Caitlin.
She also led her high school debate team
to back-to-back championships.
She went to med school.
She married Ronnie.
- Those are her memories.
- Yes, I know.
I was there.
What's your point?
Having Caitlin's memories
isn't the same as having your own.
Like you'd know anything about that.
I know it sucked sitting courtside
for the Thinker show
when he hijacked my body,
and I think that you've been
going through something similar
since Thomas died.
And after being at that funeral,
seeing that woman live
the last days of her life
to the fullest, I
think that made you want
want to start living
your best life right now.
That's not my gig, okay?
I fight the bad guys, keep Caiti safe,
and then go back in my cage.
I just have to deal with it.
Have you thought to ask
Caitlin how she feels?
What's she gonna say?
"Go ahead, Frost, take the wheel."
There's only one way to find out.
You know, Barry, I think
it's time we faced the truth.
I can't give up on Chester.
No, I meant...
About Nora.
Look, I know we keep
saying that we're fine,
but I still miss the
Nora that was, Barry,
not the Nora that will be,
and I think that you do too.
I think that's why you've been
working so hard all summer.
I thought if I could keep people safe,
that it would make up
for how much I miss her.
Think all the work this
summer and the long hours,
pushing myself, pushing the team...
It's so I could avoid
what scares me the most...
That I'll never get over this.
There is no support group
for what we're experiencing.
You know why I was at that junkyard?
I lost my purple jacket.
And I was obsessed
with getting it back because...
You know, in my mind...
Nora needs it.
You know, she needs it to become XS.
And when that thing
swallowed it, just...
just for, like, a tiny second,
I wanted it to swallow me too.
You know, the only way
we're gonna get through this
is if we carry this burden together.
It's the only way, Barry.
We just ran out of time.
Okay, so how do we get
Chester's consciousness
out of the black hole?
Well, the electrical impulses
that make up Chester's mind
are just past the
black hole's threshold,
but since his synaptic energy
has a negative charge...
I could use my
lightning's positive charge
to attract his energy.
- Like a magnet.
- Exactly.
Then what? I mean, how are you
gonna survive inside of there?
Well, your... your Speed Force aura
should protect you, right?
What if it doesn't?
The gravimetric forces will crush you
to a subatomic size within seconds.
That's not gonna happen.
The Speed Force is a
billion times stronger
than any gravimetric force.
Even if you do survive the
entry, we don't have a way
of keeping Chester's mind
intact on the way out.
We'd need superconductive wiring
from a quantum computer to do that,
and last time I checked,
those only exist in the future.
Nora.
Our Nora, she can still help us.
Oh, my God, her back-up gauntlet.
Cisco, it's still here.
That gauntlet's gonna
have the filament we need.
I'll strip it out and
thread it into your suit.
Okay, in the meantime, Ralph,
can you and Frost help
CCPD evacuate downtown?
Frost is ready to come out
and to use Cisco's present.
Captain, you shouldn't be out here!
It's my city too.
Help these people get out of here.
Yes, sir!
No!
Run, dude.
- You're welcome.
- Suit's finished.
Okay, great, so when Barry
gets Chester's consciousness
out of there, what is he supposed to do
with that energy?
- You remember the MAC?
- Yeah, but it's not working.
No, but the structural integrity
is strong enough to
contain synaptic energy.
Besides, we already moved
Chester into it, so...
I'm sorry, what? "We" moved Chester?
That's right.
I may be small, but I
can bench my body weight.
That's it.
♪ Flash ♪
I've been saving this
for the right moment
- since day one.
- Really, Cisco?
The guy is running in
and out of a black hole.
- Good point.
- Yeah.
♪ Flash! Ah-ah ♪
♪ He's a miracle ♪
That's your window, go!
♪ Flash! Ah-ah ♪
♪ King of the impossible ♪
♪ He's for every one of us ♪
♪ Stand for every one of us ♪
♪ He saves with a mighty hand ♪
♪ Every man, every woman, every child ♪
♪ It's the mighty Flash ♪
- How long before he comes out?
- Seconds.
I think.
- "You think"?
- I think.
Barry?
Barry, can you hear me?
Barry.
Barry... Barry, please, say something.
Babe, please.
Please, Barry, I can't lose you too.
♪ Flash! Ah-ah ♪
♪ King of the impossible ♪
♪ He's for every one of us ♪
Oh, my God.
Come on, let's go.
♪ Every man, every woman, every child ♪
♪ It's the mighty Flash ♪
The black hole imploded.
Chester?
Can you hear me?
Come back here, to us,
to this body, to yourself.
What up, party people?
Hey... hey, you're the Flash.
With the speeding around and
the lightning and all that.
Hey, big fan, man, big fan.
Also, where am I?
Chester is doing so much better.
I mean, don't get me wrong,
he's still, you know, glowing
in the eyes with orange dark energy,
but he's in really good spirits.
How long until he gets out?
Caitlin said his molecules
need to destabilize
at the subatomic level.
My guess is he'll
need to cook in the MAC
for another four to
six weeks, maybe more,
until he's back to normal.
Well, believe me, he is
more than happy to chill here
at S.T.A.R. Labs in the meantime.
And when he does get out, that boy knows
exactly what he wants to do.
Mm, definitely gonna ask Natalie out.
Speaking of going out,
Kamilla and I are
doing shawarma Tuesday,
so I'm gonna mosey.
Of course, moseying is a lot
harder these days post-Vibe.
Showing up to a date
in a S.T.A.R. Lab van,
not a good look.
Mm, no. I'll give you a ride.
And risk looking like my
mom just dropped me off?
Ooh, even better, you can walk.
Okay, I'm coming.
It never occurred to me
that you might want to live a life.
That's why I never
offered to let you drive,
not because I think you're
only good in a fight.
You sure?
I know it's a really big ask,
and I don't want you feeling
obligated or whatever.
Frost, you have always
been there for me,
protecting me.
Now I get to do something for you.
Besides, even though it's always felt
like you were a part of me,
for the first time, it
feels like I'm a part of you.
Thank you.
Any time.
Guess everything's
coming up frosty, huh?
Yeah, I guess.
Where do I start?
How do you, you know, live a life?
With a life coach, of course.
So, first thing's
first: the name "Killer,"
it's a little bit too
much for some folks.
Have you thought about changing it?
My mom's middle name is Anne.
I will never accept death,
not like you did.
So, what made you believe
that you could carry
Chester out of that place?
You made me believe I could do it.
I realized we could be
each other's support group,
even though it's gonna take some time.
If we can carry a
memory like this together
in our hearts, carrying
somebody's consciousness
out of a black hole?
It's a piece of cake.
Besides, how else could
I get this back for you?
I know it's not as
good as Nora's video...
It's better.
Now we have something that
we can honor Nora with.
She was pretty "schway."
What do you want?
For your universe to survive.
The plinth...
you destroyed it.
You destroyed Nora's message.
An unfortunate side effect.
But I needed to discourage you.
From doing what?
Hoping.
Your determination
is boundless, Flash...
it is one of your greatest qualities...
but you cannot avoid the coming Crisis.
Barry has five years before he vanishes.
No longer.
December 10, 2019.
On that day, he will answer the call
and make the ultimate sacrifice.
Soon...
this world will fight for the fate
of all the known universes.
I'm not gonna leave my family.
There has to be a way
to stop what's coming.
I am sorry,
but events have been set into motion
that you cannot possibly comprehend.
I don't need to understand them!
Just tell me what I can do.
To survive?
You can't.
In order for billions to survive
this coming Crisis,
the Flash must die.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --